DALE LARSEN

Senior Software Developer And Manager

Contact

Address

Ogden, UT, 84404

E-mail

dale@dalelarsen.com

WWW

https://dalelarsen.com

Skills

Team & Project Management

Excellent

Javascript

Excellent

Angular

Excellent

ReactJS

Excellent

Node.Js

Excellent

Java

Excellent

CSS/SCSS/SASS

Excellent

Senior Software Developer and Manager

I lead, architect, manage, and build web applications and business technical solutions, and see them through to completion.

Self-taught by running a web development company for over 12 years. I have learned and developed skills in project/team management as well as many programming languages, frameworks, and libraries.

I am self-motivated and have proven that I can deliver short and long term needs. I thrive when working on projects that benefit people. I currently work in a co-working space where I have been thriving for years. I can manage remote and in-house developers. I work very well

For more info and a showcase of projects please go to https://dalelarsen.com

in both remote and in-house environments.

Work History

2015-09 -Current

Senior Software Development Manager

Fabuso, Ogden, UT

- Led and ran all the development and technology business needs of the company.
- Oversaw the acquisition of new clients and managed our development team, developing much of the software myself.
- Each new client involved building new custom software solutions, integrating 3rd party software, and migrating old systems to the corresponding replacements.
- Continued to fulfill previous duties of Senior Full Stack Developer.
- Tech: Javascript, Node.js, Angular, TypeScript, React, Java, AWS, Linux, Jenkins, Docker, SCSS, MySQL, HTML5, Firebase, Ionic, Mocha, REST, GIT, GraphQL, NoSQL

2007-11 -2015-09

Senior Full Stack Developer

Fabuso, Ogden, UT

- Architected web applications, reviewing each project and choosing frameworks and solutions that best fit each one.
- Managed development projects.
- Built and maintained software according to client

SQL and NoSQL Databases

AWS

Excellent

Excellent

Remote Work

Excellent

For all see "Technologies"

needs.

 Tech: Javascript, AngularJs, Java, AWS, Jenkins, Linux, CSS, jQuery, MySQL, HTML5, Firebase, REST, GIT, NoSQL

2002-09 -2005-11

Website Manager

Achieve Auto Sales, Ogden, UT

 Maintained company website for car dealership.
 Kept up to date daily inventory on website and launched and managed eBay® listings for the cars.

Technologies

Angular 2+ (3 years), Javascript (10+ years), React (2 years), Jquery (10+ years), Nodejs (4 years), Angularjs (6 years), Java (9 years), AWS (8 years), CSS (10+ years), Firebase (4 years), MySQL (10+ years), Web Development (10+ years), PHP, VueJS (2 years), Jenkins, ChartJS, Mocha, Gatsby, TypeScript (4 years), Ionic, Photoshop (10+ years), Adobe XD (2 years), Git (5 years), Bootstrap (6 years), APIs, User Interface (UI), JSON, XML, GitHub, MVC, NoSQL, AJAX, SVN (10+ years), Scrum, HTML5

Projects

For a showcase of projects please go to https://dalelarsen.com

Education

2002-08 -2005-05

High school: Computer Science

Roy High School - Roy, UT

References

- Kurt Othmer President/CEO at EEGInfo, Inc: (818) 970-5878
- Shaye Larsen CEO/Owner at West Bridge Auto Sales, Partner at Fabuso: (801) 388-4721

- Jared Hancock Business Coach/Consultant: (801) 389-8593
- Nick Drishinski Software Developer at Rockford Fosgate: (435) 757-9991
- Michael Wilson Director, Medicare Sales at eHealth, Inc: (801) 564-0879